SAMUEL IWELUMO

Lagos, NG 102101 samueliwelumo@gmail.com 2347047672684

Diligent and passionate software engineer with 1 year experience and a proven knowledge of software development. Worked with front end languages and frameworks like

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, ReactJS, etc and also back-end languages and frameworks like NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, Flask, MySQL, SQLAlchemy etc. Knowledgeable in user interface, testing and debugging processes. Also skilled in Devops practices like Web Server configuration, Load Balancing and Firewall configuration, HTTPS and SSL, Database management and replicating, etc. Bringing forth a motivated attitude and a variety of powerful skills to successfully accomplish a set goal as team player.

Work Experience

Software Engineering Intern

ALX - Ojo, Lagos

September 2022 to Present

- Build software using Python, JavaScript, C, etc
- Perform and submit tasks before specified deadlines
- · Write automated tests for software products built using python doc test and unit tests
- Successfully worked with a team to build a bash shell using the C programming language
- · Successfully worked with a team to create a clone of the AirBnB website from building to deploying
- Devops practices

Customer Service Specialist

Simon Finance - Lagos, Nigeria. September 2021 to July 2022

- Came up with ideas and strategies that greatly reduced customer complaints.
- Provide appropriate solutions for customers.
- Explored options to massively grow and maintain customer network.
- Followed up to resolve any issue experienced by the customer.

Head of IT and Accounting-Intern

KD Stakeholders Limited - Lagos, Nigeria. January 2021 to August 2021

- Created and edited customer profiles with Excel and generated payment lists using the generated profiles.
- Conducted classes for staffs and gave ideas on how to best manage the computers and software.
- Teamed up with 5 people and created great ideas in creating their official website

IT and Computer Instructor

Galaxy Computer College - Lagos, Nigeria. January 2019 to January 2020

- Conducted training for students on designing and ultimately helped them become better designers
- Had my first experience with web designing and made some designs.
- Participated in training programs and instructor workshops to improve the company.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

The West African Union University - Cotonou, Benin October 2016 to July 2020

Skills

- JavaScript
- CSS
- Git
- APIs
- HTML5
- Node.js
- MySQL
- React
- REST
- Unit Testing
- Bootstrap
- GitHub
- DevOps
- Front-End Development
- User Interface (UI)
- C
- MongoDB
- Web services
- · Load balancing
- Python
- jQuery
- Firewall

Languages

• English - Fluent

Links

http://Linkedin.com/in/iwelumo

http://Twitter.com/micoliser

https://www.GitHub.com/micoliser

Certifications and Licenses

JavaScript Essential Training - LinkedIn

CSS Essential Training - LinkedIn

HTML Essential Training - LinkedIn

The 2022 Web Development Bootcamp - Udemy

Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End - LinkedIn

Excel Essential Training - LinkedIn